Guide to the Administrative Papers of the President George Bugliarello RG.006
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
- Series IV: Organizations
  - Subseries H: Miscellaneous, 1978-1995
    - Brooklyn Chamber of Commerce – Business-Education Committee, 1987 March-1988 November (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Comtech (Telecommunications Corp.), 1989, 1993; Undated (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Egypt-U.S. Joint Consultative Council for Applied Science and Technology Research, 1978 May (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Financial Services Technology Consortium (FinTech) – Miscellaneous, Handwritten notes, 1990-1993 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Lord Corporation, 1993-1994 (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Marconi International Fellowship – Promotional Material, Undated (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Mayor's Award for Science & Technology – RESTRICT, 1993 May-September (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - Mayor's Commission for Science and Technology, 1989 December (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - M.I.T. Alumni Association, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - National Academic of Sciences (NAS) - Proposed articles, Drafts - 1 - RESTRICT, 1980 (Box 38, Folder 21)
    - NAS - Proposed articles, Drafts - 2 - RESTRICT, 1980 (Box 38, Folder 22)
    - NAS - Proposed articles, Drafts - 3 - RESTRICT, 1980 (Box 38, Folder 23)
    - National Medal of Technology - Nomination Committee, 1989 July-1991 February (Box 38, Folder 24)
    - National Medal of Technology - Nomination Committee Forms, 1990-1991 (Box 38, Folder 25)
    - NRC (National Research Council), 1992 (Box 38, Folder 26)
    - NRC, 1993-1994 (Box 38, Folder 27)
    - National Science Foundation, 1990, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 28)
    - Pi Kappa Phi Fraternity, 1976 (Box 38, Folder 29)
    - Regional Plan Association, 1992 July-1994 March (Box 38, Folder 30)
    - United Nations – World Engineering Partnership for Sustainable Development (WEPSD), 1993 April (Box 38, Folder 31)
    - United Nations - Commission on Science and Technology – Gender Working Group, 1994 November-December (Box 38, Folder 32)
- Series V: Speeches & Symposia
  This series contains transcripts and notes from speeches and lectures given by George Bugliarello at national and international conferences, symposiums and other events.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Subseries A: Speeches
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1973-1974 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1974; 1976 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1977 January-November (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1978 March-October (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1979 March-September (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1980 February-March (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1980 April-October (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1981 December; Undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1981 December; Undated (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1982 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1984 February-December (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1985 May-December (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1986 February-December (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1987 February-November; Undated (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1988 February-December (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1989 January-November (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1990 February-March (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1990 May-July (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1990 August-November (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Speeches – Miscellaneous, 1993 February-October (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Speeches - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - "Technology and Education" – 9th World Conference of Correspondence Education – Airlie House, VA, 1972 May (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - "University Industry Interaction" – Long Island Association, 1975 January 15 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - "Industry- University Interaction is Good for Business" – Advancement for Commerce and Industry, 1975 January 15 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Othmer, Don, 1975 February 1 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - "The Biosoma: The Coming Together of Biological Organisms, Social Organisms and Machines" – Monmouth Junior Science Symposium, 1975 March 6 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - "The Development of Technology-Based Industry on Long Island – Conference at Polytechnic Institute of New York At Farmingdale, 1975 May 10 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - WQXR Statement - Long Island, NY, 1975 June 3 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - "Technology Units in City Government "– New York State Charter Revision Commission, 1975 June 16 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - "Remarks at University of the International Association of Universities – Moscow University, 1975 August 21 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Speech to the Faculty – Polytechnic University, 1975 September (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Testimony at Hearing on New York State Economic Redevelopment Authority Act – World Trade Center, 1975 September 30 (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - "Universities of the Community in the United States and the Socialist Countries – University of Illinois at Urbana, 1975 October 10 (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Bern Dibner Tribute, 1975 October 21 (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - "L'Universita, La Facolta' Di Ingegniria E La Comunita", 1975 December 17 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - "American Ingenuity At the Bicentennial" – Joint Meeting of the New York City Chapter of the National Society of Professional Engineers and the New York City Section of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers – Engineers Club, New York City, 1976 February (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - "Coating Technology – An Outsider's View of the Industry" – St. Louis, Missouri, 1976 February (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - Administrative Leadership, 1976 February 3 (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - Introductory Remarks – Address by Senator Henry Jackson – Long Island, New York, 1976 March 26 (Box 40, Folder 23)
    - "Technology and the Corporation" – Engineer's Day, Lord Corporation, 1976 April (Box 40, Folder 24)
    - "Technology, Values, and Engineering Systems" – Symposium on Technology and the Spirit of Man – University of Iowa, 1976 April 19 (Box 40, Folder 25)
    - Welcome Speech – Microwave Research Institute (MRI), 1976 April 20 (Box 40, Folder 26)
    - "Perspectives in Biomechanics Research and Education Over the Past Ten Years" - Waterloo, Canada, 1976 May 26 (Box 40, Folder 27)
    - Faculty & Corporation Meeting, 1976 June (Box 40, Folder 28)
    - Commencement Address – Polytechnic Institute of New York - Carnegie Hall, 1976 June 2 (Box 40, Folder 29)
    - Polytechnic Institute of New York at Farmingdale – Long Island, New York, 1976 July 13 (Box 40, Folder 30)
    - Corporation Meeting, 1976 October 13 (Box 40, Folder 31)
    - Remarks on the Occasion of a Luncheon in Honor of Senator James Buckley – Farmingdale, Long Island, NY, 1976 October 14 (Box 40, Folder 32)
    - Gruman Hall Dedication, 1976 December 23 (Box 40, Folder 33)
    - "We Must Develop a Stronger Technological Base for Long Island" – World Gateway Executive Forum Breakfast, 1977 August 17 (Box 40, Folder 34)
    - "The Problem of Industry-University Interaction" – Conference on Engineering and Science Research for Industrial Development" – Easton, MA, 1977 October 3-7 (Box 40, Folder 35)
    - "The New Engineering Ethics" – Rochester, New York, 1978 June 5 (Box 40, Folder 36)
    - "The Paint and Coating Industry Hypothesis for the Future" - Science of Organic Coatings Conference – Kent State University, 1978 June 20-22 (Box 40, Folder 37)
    - "Graduate Programs in Engineering and our National Needs" – Engineering Foundation Conference – Henniker, New Hampshire, 1978 July 11 (Box 40, Folder 38)
    - "For a Stronger Industry-University Interaction" – Key Note, Conference on Mechanisms of University-Industry Interaction – Reston, Virginia, 1978 December 7 (Box 40, Folder 39)
    - "A Note on Orientation and Curriculum for Technological Education in Nigeria", 1979 April 10 (Box 40, Folder 40)
    - Radio and Television, 1979-1980 (Box 40, Folder 41)
    - College Presidents' Panel, "Long Island Colleges Move to Meet Long Island's Growing Technology Education Needs" - Long Island Forum for Technology Breakfast, 1984 September 13 (Box 40, Folder 42)
    - "Technology and the Environment" – International Conference "Man's Role in Changing the Global Environment" - Venice, Italy, 1985 October 22 (Box 40, Folder 43)
    - "University and the Small Entrepreneur" –Peat Marwick, Venture Capital Group, 1985 October (Box 40, Folder 44)
    - Chemistry Symposium, 1985 November 22 (Box 40, Folder 45)
    - "Science and Technology and Religion" - Religion in America - Princeton Club, New York, New York, 1985 December 3 (Box 40, Folder 46)
    - Carnegie Mellon University, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 47)
    - "National Center for Space Electronics – Proposal, 1986 January (Box 40, Folder 48)
    - Colleges and Universities Versus Schools: Shall The Twins Meet?" – National Technology Literacy Conference – Baltimore, Maryland, 1986 February 16 (Box 40, Folder 49)
    - Weber Dedication, 1986 March (Box 40, Folder 50)
    - Polytechnic Institute of New York at Westchester Dinner Speech – John R. Opel, 1986 May (Box 40, Folder 51)
    - "Research & Development for Macroprojects" – Symposium on Governmental Management of Technological Change, 1986 May 30 (Box 40, Folder 52)
    - "Fluid Mechanics in Civil Engineering: The Crisis and the Opportunity" – Dinner Address, ASCE Special Conference on Advancements in Aerodynamics, Fluid Mechanics and Hydraulics – Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1986 June 4 (Box 40, Folder 53)
    - Minneapolis Speech Notes (see folder 53), undated (Box 40, Folder 54)
    - Sal Nuzzo Dinner – Long Island, NY, 1986 September (Box 40, Folder 55)
    - "Business, Industry and the University" – Erie, Pennsylvania, 1986 October (Box 40, Folder 56)
    - Board Meeting / Retreat Address, 1986 October 30-November 1 (Box 40, Folder 57)
    - "Lo Spazio Dell'ingegneria Nella Scienza Moderna" Conference – Torino, Italy, 1987 October (Box 40, Folder 58)
    - "The Future of Science" – Achievement Rewards for College Scientists (ARCS) – Hotel Pierre, New York City, 1991 May 15 (Box 40, Folder 59)
    - Third International Conference on Management of Technology – University of Miami, 1992 February 17-21 (Box 40, Folder 60)
    - "Technology Transfer: A Socio-Technological Paradigm" – Presentation at the Symposium on Development and Transfer of Industry Technology – 20th Anniversary Celebration of the Industrial Technology Research Institute – Taipei, Taiwan, 1993 July 6-7 (Box 40, Folder 61)
    - "La Regione Giuliano- Dalmata – Una Veduta della sua storia e del Suo Futuro" – Al Convegno Internazionale Dell Associazione – New York, 1993 September 5 (Box 40, Folder 62)
    - "Bridge Between American and Italian Engineering Education & Research" – Seminar – Polytechnic University, 1993 September 21 (Box 40, Folder 63)
    - "The Role of University, Industry and International Collaboration" – Seminar on Changing Characteristics of Science and Technology in International Development – National Research Council - Washington D.C., 1993 September 27 (Box 40, Folder 64)
    - "The Role of Universities in Charting a Path" – Seminar on Changing Characteristics of Science and Technology in International Development – National Research Council – Washington, DC, 1993 October 2 (Box 40, Folder 65)
    - "Thoughts on the Future of Science and Engineering" – Commencement Address, Illinois Institute of Technology, 1993 December 19 (Box 40, Folder 66)
    - "The Future of Engineering" – Polytechnic University at Westchester, 1994 February (Box 40, Folder 67)
    - Material for possible use in speeches, 1978-1989 (Box 40, Folder 68)
    - Commencement, undated (Box 40, Folder 69)
    - "Computer and Soviet Society" – New School for Social Research, Undated (Box 40, Folder 70)
    - "How Science and Engineering Operate", Undated (Box 40, Folder 71)
    - Overhead Projection Slides – Lectures, Undated (Box 40, Folder 72)
  - Subseries B: Symposia
    - 1st International Symposium on the History and Philosophy of Technology - University of Illinois as Columbus Circle - Discussion Paper Drafts - 1, 1973-1975 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - 1st International Symposium on the History and Philosophy of Technology - University of Illinois as Columbus Circle - Discussion Paper Drafts - 2, 1973-1975 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - 1st International Symposium on the History and Philosophy of Technology - University of Illinois as Columbus Circle - Discussion Paper Drafts - 3, 1973-1975 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - 1st International Symposium on the History and Philosophy of Technology - University of Illinois as Columbus Circle - Discussion Paper Drafts - 4, 1973-1975 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - 1st International Symposium on the History and Philosophy of Technology - University of Illinois as Columbus Circle - Discussion Paper Drafts - 5, 1973-1975 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - 1st International Symposium on the History and Philosophy of Technology - University of Illinois as Columbus Circle - Discussion Paper Drafts - 6, 1973-1975 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - 1st International Symposium on the History and Philosophy of Technology - University of Illinois as Columbus Circle - Discussion Paper Drafts - 7, 1973-1975 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - 1st International Symposium on the History and Philosophy of Technology - University of Illinois as Columbus Circle - Discussion Paper Drafts - 8, 1973-1975 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - 1st International Symposium on the History and Philosophy of Technology - University of Illinois as Columbus Circle - Discussion Paper Drafts - 9, 1973-1975 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - "Education of the Inventor" - Annual Meeting of the American Society of Engineering Education - Knoxville, Tennessee, 1976 June 16 (Box 41, Folder 10)
- Series VI: Publications & Manuscripts
  This series contains published books and published and unpublished articles written and edited by George Bugliarello as well as his handwritten notes and research material he used for various publications. Subseries f: Books contains autographed copies of books by other authors addressed to George Bugliarello and Gioia Marconi Braga, daughter of Guglielmo Marconi, founder of the Marconi International Fellowship Foundation.
  The publications have been assigned a number based on a numbering system adopted by the President's office to keep track of publications. Please see Box 42 / Folder 1 "List of Publications" for a complete list of George Bugliarello's publications compiled in October 2011.
  This series is arranged by document type. The publications and reports and newspaper articles are arranged according to the publication number assigned by the donor and are otherwise ordered chronologically.
  - subseries A: Publications and Reports
    - List of Publications, 1953-1985 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Clipping Book - M1-M17, 1970-1979 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - M1 – "Society, Technology and the College of Engineering", 1970 January (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - M2 – "On Meta-Technology", 1970 October (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - M3 - "On the State of the College and Other Matters" (University of Illinois, Chicago Circle), 1970 December (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - M5 – "The Professional School and Chicago Circle", 1972 May 12 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - M6 – "Some World Views of Technology", 1974 December (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - M7 – "Technology, the University and the Community: A Delicate Balance", 1975 March 13 (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - M8 – "Industry-University Interaction is Good For Business", 1975 January 15 (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - M9 – "The Biosoma: The Coming Together of Biological Organisms, Social Organizations and Machines", 1975 March 6 (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - M10 – "New York or New Byzantium?", 1975 June 2 (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - M12 - "Technology and the Corporation" – Lord Corporation, 1976 April 23 (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - M13 - "Introduction--Part I. The Brooklyn Bridge in Perspective: Its Building and Its Builders", 1984 (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - M15 – "Il Parco Tecnologico: Note Sulle Risorse, Competenze Ed Organizzazione", 1991 (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - T1 - "Technology Units in City Government", 1975 June 16 (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - T3 - Testimony at Joint Hearing of Senate & Assembly Higher Education Committees, 1975 December 3 (Box 41, Folder 26)
    - T4 - Statement to Board of Estimate on Jay St. Fire House, 1975 December 4 (Box 41, Folder 27)
    - T5 - Long Island as the Seri Site, 1975 December 19 (Box 41, Folder 28)
    - #3 – "La Resistenza al Moto Accelerato di Sfere in Acqua", 1956 February (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - #4 – "Pertinent Factors in Flow Research on Dilute Fiber Suspensions", 1957 June (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - #6 – "Effects of Fibers on Velocity Distribution, Turbulence and Flow Resistance of Dilute Suspensions", 1958 October (Box 41, Folder 31)
    - #7 – "Impianti Elioelettrici", 1958 (Box 41, Folder 32)
    - #8 – "A Particular Non-Newtonian Flow-- Dilute Fiber Suspension", 1959 July (Box 41, Folder 33)
    - #10 – "Fluid Mechanics – Its Scope and Challenge", 1961 May (Box 41, Folder 34)
    - #12 – "The Water Resources Problem in Haiti--A Case for the Interdisciplinary Approach", 1962 (Box 41, Folder 35)
    - #13 – "Electronic Computer Use in Scoping Power Projects", 1961 July (Box 41, Folder 36)
    - #14 – "Toward a Computer Language for Hydraulic Engineering", 1961 (Box 41, Folder 37)
    - #15 – "Basic Data for Dilute Fiber Sus¬pension in Uniform Flow with Shear", 1961 July (Box 41, Folder 38)
    - #16 – "Rheological Models and Laminar Shear Flow of Fiber Suspensions", 1961 December (Box 41, Folder 39)
    - #17 – "I. Moti Non-Newtonian nell'Ingegneria Idraulica (Non-Newtonian Flows in Hydraulic Engineering)", 1962 (Box 41, Folder 40)
    - #18 – "Une Revue des Resources Hydrauliques en Haiti" (A Review of the Hydraulic Resources of Haiti), 1962 April (Box 41, Folder 41)
    - #19 – "High-speed Microcinematographic Studies of Blood Flow in Vitro", 1962 (Box 41, Folder 42)
    - #20 – "Detailed Characteristics of the Flow of Blood In Vitro", 1963 (Box 41, Folder 43)
    - #21 – "Some Considerations of the Analysis and Design of Hydraulic Machinery for Non-Newtonian Fluids", 1963 (Box 41, Folder 44)
    - #22 – "The Rule of Flood Plains in the Correlation Between Flood Predictions and Dam Design", 1963 (Box 41, Folder 45)
    - #23 - "Phase Separation in Suspensions Flowing Through Bifurcations: A Simplified Hemodynamic Model", 1964 January 31 (Box 41, Folder 46)
    - #24 – "Flow of Clay-Water Suspensions", 1964 (Box 41, Folder 47)
    - #25 – "Man-Machine Communication in Civil Engineering", 1964 (Box 41, Folder 48)
    - #26 – "The Mechanism of Phase Separation at Bifurications", 1964 (Box 41, Folder 49)
    - #27 – "Random Walk Study of Convective Diffusion", 1964 August (Box 41, Folder 50)
    - #28 – "The Profile Viscosity and Other Characteristics of Blood Flow", 1965 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - #29 – "Bio-Engineering As a New Dialogue", 1965 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - #30 – "Exploratory Studies on the Stochastic Simulation of Outfall Flows", 1965 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - #31 – "Hospitals", 1965 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - #32 – "Microcirculation Hemodynamics and other Bio Flow Problems", 1965 April (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - #33 – "Mathematical Representation of an Urban Flood Plan", 1965 March (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - #34 – "Non-Newtonian Flows", 1965 August (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - #35 – "A Simplified Model of the Flow in the Plasmatic Gaps of the Smaller Circulatory Vessels", 1965 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - #36 – "An Engineering Oriented View of Biological Flows", 1966 October 12-14 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - #37 – "Engineering Implications of Biological Flow Process", 1966 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - #39 – "Concentration Redistribution Phenomena in the Shear Flow of Monolayers of Suspended Particles", 1966 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - #40 – "Hydro – A Computer Language for Water Resources Engineering", 1966 November (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - #41 – "Design Philosophy, Specifications, and Implications of Hydro", 1967 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - #42 – "Random Walk Study of Convective Division", 1964 August (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - #43 – "Programming Needs in the Water Resources Field and the Role of a Problem Oriented Language", 1966 November (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - #44 – "Study of Convective Diffusion from Continuous Point Sources By a Random Walk Model", 1966 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - #45 – "Model Studies of the Hydronamic Characteristics of an Erythrocyte", 1966 (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - #46 - "Stochastic Simulation of the Diffusion of Jets", 1967 (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - #63 - "A Stochastic Model of Convective Diffusion from a Continuous Source", 1969 (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - #70 - "An Introduction to the Stochastic Simulation of Flow Processes", 1966 September 7 (Box 42, Folder 20)
    - #85 – "Large Socio-Technological Systems: Human Conflict and Human Design", 1970 (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - #112 - "The New Phase in Engineering Education: Engineering and the New Liberal Education", 1973 February (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - #115 - Socio-Technology: The Emergence of a New Ideology & A New Technology, 1973 May (Box 42, Folder 23)
    - #131 – Biofluidmechanics, 1977 June (Box 42, Folder 24)
    - #133 - "The Biosoma: The Coming Together of Man, Society and Machines", 1978 July (Box 42, Folder 25)
    - #135 – "Expanding Your Research Capabilities", 1978 June 7 (Box 42, Folder 26)
    - #136 – "Perspectives in Biomechanics Research and Education for Next Decade", 1978 February (Box 42, Folder 27)
    - #137 – "Blood Flow in Straight and Curved Capillary Glass Tubes", 1979 (Box 42, Folder 28)
    - #138 - "Engineering Education for the 21st Century, To Respond to the Needs of Space Systems Engineering", 1979 (Box 42, Folder 29)
    - #139 – "Technology & Society: It's Time to Wake up to the Problems", 1978 September 28-29 (Box 42, Folder 30)
    - #149 - "The Role of the University Assisting Industry in the Fulfillment of the National and Regional Needs", 1979 (Box 42, Folder 31)
    - #159 - "Development of Urban Research Parks", 1983 (Box 42, Folder 32)
    - #160 – "The Generation of Knowledge in Advanced Countries", 1984 (Box 42, Folder 33)
    - #175 - Technology in Society – "Editor's Note", 1984 (Box 42, Folder 34)
    - #187 - "Socio-Technology and Systems Analysis and Engineering", 1986 (Box 42, Folder 35)
    - #198 - "Toward Hyperintelligence", 1988 September (Box 42, Folder 36)
    - #200 - "Technology & the Environment", 1989 (Box 42, Folder 37)
    - #206 – "Science and Technology in New York City for the 21st Century", 1989 December (Box 42, Folder 38)
    - #214 - "Engineering & Its Social Function: A Current Assessment", 1990 October 3 (Box 42, Folder 39)
    - #217 - "New Trends in Research Management", 1991 April 17-19 (Box 42, Folder 40)
    - #223 – "How Long Will We Continue to Accept the Dismantling of our Industry?", 1992 January (Box 42, Folder 41)
    - #227 - "The Ideal of Civil Engineering", 1994 July (Box 42, Folder 42)
    - #229 - "Science at the Crossroads", 1993 February 25 (Box 42, Folder 43)
    - #231 - "Technology Transfer: A Socio-Technological Paradigm", 1994 (Box 42, Folder 44)
    - #232 - "Metrotech: An Urban University Industry Park", 1993 Spring (Box 42, Folder 45)
    - #233 - "The Role of the University in Charting a Path for the Twenty-first Century", 1993 October (Box 42, Folder 46)
    - #236 - "The Future of Bioengineering", 1994 (Box 42, Folder 47)